Hardit Singh

972.750.0578; singh.hardit@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/HarditSingh Website: www.harditsingh.net

SUMMARY: Versatile professional with skills in financial modeling, analysis, programming and data science. Awarded MBA in finance, with over 7 years of business experience. Eager to learn new things, and am constantly looking for intellectually challenging projects. I am currently pursuing my interest in programming, and have 1000+hours of coding experience.

KEY SKILLS

Tools and Technologies:

- Programing Python, Ruby and JavaScript
- Frontend: AngularJS, HTML and CSS
- Backend: Python, Flask, Rails, JavaScript, NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Database: MySQL and MongoDB
- Other: GitHub and Linux, terminal Advanced MS Excel, Knowledge of databases like Bloomberg and Reuters

Skills:

- Web Development
- Data analysis using Python
- Financial Modeling
- Financial Analysis
- Valuation

CERTIFICATIONS

Web development using Ruby on Rails from Coding Dojo
 Web development using MongoDb, Express, Angular and NodeJS from Coding Dojo
 Web development in Python (Using Flask and MYSQL) from Coding Dojo
 HTML and CSS from Coding Dojo
 SQL beginner, intermediate and advance course from Dataquest.io
 Data visualization course from Dataquest.io
 Python for data sciences from Dataquest.io
 May 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Resident (October 2016 – Present)

Coding Dojo: An immersive coding boot camp in Dallas, TX.

- Developed and deployed websites using MEAN, Python and Ruby on Rails stacks
- Created fully integrated website including setting up the database.
- All deployed projects are showcased at harditsingh.net

RELAVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Finance Manager

(September 2014 – December 2014)

Taxi for Sure: A tech startup - Bangalore, India

- Managed a team of 9 people with 2 direct reports.
- Key person in company's fund raising initiative. Built a fully integrated model for the company befitting its
 unique business model and coordinated with various departments within the company to supply information
 for the pitch book.
- Was in charge of management reporting, both routine and ad hoc. Assisted management with financial modeling required to evaluate various projects.
- Assisted with planning and budgeting. Coordinated goal optimization with branch heads and senior management. Allocated funds according to macro and micro organizational goals.

Senior Analyst (August 2013 – August 2014)

Copal Amba Research: A Moody's analytics company - Bangalore, India

- Assisted key senior level clients in planning and executing internal programs. Ran a data quality program and reduced the number of issues from 300+ down to the single digits.
- Prepared various periodic presentations and performance reports that were directly published by the client.
- In charge of troubleshooting internal data management system issues for analysts based in Asia.

Hardit Singh

972.750.0578; singh.hardit@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/HarditSingh Website: www.harditsingh.net

Senior Analyst (March 2011 – August 2013)

Copal Amba Research: A Moody's analytics company - Bangalore, India

- Assisted clients based in Asia Pacific region with building and maintaining financial models, setting up research reports and presentations, and updating internal data base from various external databases.
- Trained team members and performed quality checks for all products.

Analyst (June 2008 – March 2011)

Copal Amba Research: A Moody's analytics company - Bangalore, India

- Assisted UK based fund manager with various areas of buy-side equity research.
- Built and maintained complex financial models for various companies by identifying key business drivers, preparing models where all financial statements are fully integrated, and forecasting the compiled statements.
- Created a template where models can be quickly built by either pulling numbers form Reuters, or by plugging
 in a sell-side model.
- Performed ad hock open-ended research, and built situation specific models for scenario analysis. Eg.
 Analyzed the impact of commodity price fluctuations based on financial statements of metal and mining companies.

Intern (April 2007 – May 2007)

Copal Amba Research: A Moody's analytics company - Bangalore, India

- Built financial models, and wrote company profiles for a bulge bracket investment bank.
- Was one of the only 3 people who were given a pre-placement offer after University.

EDUCATION

Christ University - Bangalore India

(May 2008)

MBA, Finance

OTHER INFORMATION

Open to travel and relocate Authorized to work for anyone and eligible for H1B